Rienow, Leona; Papers mss025
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Typescripts, ca. 1952-1955; Undated; 1; 2 cubic ft.
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter II, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 105)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter III, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 106)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter III-A, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 107)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter IV, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 108)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter V, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 109)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter VI, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 110)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter VII, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 111)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter VIII, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 112)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter IX, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 113)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter X, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 114)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter XI, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 115)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter XIII, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 116)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter XIV, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 117)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter XV, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 118)
  - Pea Soup and Snails, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 119)
  - Peeking Gendarmes, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 120)
  - Professor Your Good Will is Showing!, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 121)
  - River Without Any End, Title Page, Author's Note, Chapter I, 1951-1952 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 122)
  - River Without Any End, Synopsis, 1951-1952 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 123)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter I, 1951-1952 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 124)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter II, 1951-1952 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 125)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter III, 1952 May (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 126)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter IV, 1951-1952 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 127)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter V, 1951-1952 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 128)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter VI, 1951-1952 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 129)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter VII, 1951-1952 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 130)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter VIII, 1951-1952 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 131)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter IX, 1951-1952 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 132)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XI, 1951-1952 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 133)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XII, 1952 May (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 134)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XII a, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 135)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XIII, 1951-1952 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 136)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XIV, 1951-1952 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 137)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XV, 1952 May (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 138)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XVI, 1951-1952 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 139)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XVII, 1951-1952 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 140)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XVIII, 1951-1952 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 141)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XIX, 1951-1952 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 142)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XX, 1951-1952 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 143)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XXI, 1951-1952 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 144)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XXII, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 145)
  - River Without Any End, Chapter XXIII, 1951-1952 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 146)
  - River Without Any End, Source Bibliography, 1951-1952 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 147)
  - Screwball Authorities: Our Idolatry of Big Names, 1940 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 148)
  - Tourists Delight, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 149)
  - You Can't Buck Tradition, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 150)
  - Unbottled Scotch, 1987 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 151)
  - We Become Class-Conscious, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 152)
- Research Materials, 1856-1960; 2; 0.45 cubic ft.
  This series contains research materials that Leona Train Rienow used for her books, short stories, and articles. There are many whole newspaper sections pertaining to Duluth, Minnesota and mining in Minnesota, as well as Photostats of land records dating from the nineteenth century. There are also magazines and brochures, as well as drawings of floorplans, materials on the history of many towns in England, and interviews of miners, including her father.
  - Alfred, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 1)
  - Archaeology, 1937-1938 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 2)
  - Arts and Trade, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 3)
  - Atomic Peril, 1960 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 4)
  - Chronology, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 5)
  - Chronology of Reigns, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 6)
  - Churches and Nunneries, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 7)
  - Corrections, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 8)
  - Count, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 9)
  - Countryside, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 10)
  - Customs, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 11)
  - Danes, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 12)
  - Dress and Accoutrements, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 13)
  - Ethelfleda's Parents, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 14)
  - Ethelwulf, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 15)
  - Fleda, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 16)
  - Floor Plans, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 17)
  - The Friar's Lantern, 1948 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 18)
  - Kent, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 19)
  - Laws, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 20)
  - Lemner Manuscript, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 21)
  - Life in New York-Driftwood, 1932 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 22)
  - Life in 10th Century Britain, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 23)
  - Locusts, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 24)
  - Logging, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 25)
  - London, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 26)
  - Maps, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 27)
  - McCarthy's Beach Project I, 1938-1953 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 28)
  - McCarthy's Beach Project II, 1938-1953 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 29)
  - McCarthy's Beach Project III, 1938-1953 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 30)
  - Medical Facts, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 31)
  - Mesaba Historical I, 1856-1948 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 32)
  - Mesaba Historical II, 1888-1958 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 33)
  - Mesaba Historical III, 1888-1958 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 34)
  - Mining, 1933-1936 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 35)
  - Minnesota, 1888-1939 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 36)
  - Minnesota, 1938-1939 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 37)
  - Moscow, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 38)
  - Poems and Ballads, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 39)
  - Peoples, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 40)
  - Pioneering, 1909-1947 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 41)
  - Politics, ca. 1950 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 42)
  - Popes, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 43)
  - Preparing Students for the Job Market, 1941 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 44)
  - Prince Valiant, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 45)
  - Resources, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 46)
  - River Without Any End, 1935-1941 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 47)
  - Rochester, England, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 48)
  - Sapon Building, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 49)
  - Surveys, 1960 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 50)
  - Tappan, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 51)
  - Winchester, Wessex, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 52)
  - Youth Organizations, 1948-1949 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 53)
- Correspondence, 1946-1988; 3; 0.33 cubic ft.
  This series consists of letters exchanged between Leona Train Rienow and various editors and publishing houses in her search to get her works published. In some cases, there are both Rienow's letters and those of the editor or publisher. In other cases, only the editor's or publisher's letters remain.
  - The American Home, 1959 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 54)
  - Better Homes and Gardens, 1960 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 55)
  - The Board of Education and Publication of the American Baptist Convention, 1952 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 56)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 57)
  - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1963 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 58)
  - The Children's Friend, Undated (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 59)
  - Children's Play Mate Magazine, Undated (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 60)
  - Christian Herald Magazine, 1952 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 61)
  - Dodd, Mead & Company, 1951 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 62)
  - Doubleday & Company, 1950 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 63)
  - Every Woman's, ca. 1959-1960 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 64)
  - Girl's Fun and Fashion Magazine, 1952 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 65)
  - Girls Today, 1952-1953 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 66)
  - Good Housekeeping, 1959 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 67)
  - Harcourt-Brace, 1952-1953 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 68)
  - Harper and Brothers, 1951 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 69)
  - Harper's Bazaar, 1960 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 70)
  - Hougton-Mifflin Company, 1946-1955 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 71)
  - Ives Vernon, 1952 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 72)
  - Jack and Jill, Undated (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 73)
  - Julian Messner, Undated (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 74)
  - Ladies Home Journal, 1959 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 75)
  - Lippincott, Company, 1951-1952 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 76)
  - List of Editors, Undated (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 77)
  - Little Brown & Company, 1946-1952 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 78)
  - Longmans, Green & Company, 1946-1954 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 79)
  - Macrae-Smith Company, 1953 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 80)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc., 1953 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 81)
  - The Methodist Church, 1949-1955 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 82)
  - Methodist Publications, Undated (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 83)
  - Oxford Books, 1951 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 84)
  - G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1952 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 85)
  - Random House, 1951 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 86)
  - The Reader's Digest, 1959 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 87)
  - Redbook Magazine, 1959 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 88)
  - Leona Train Rienow, Biographical Information, Undated (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 89)
  - Scribner's Sons, 1947-1949 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 90)
  - Senior Prom, 1951 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 91)
  - Seventeen, 1950 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 92)
  - Simon & Schuster, 1951-1953 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 93)
  - The Star Weekly, 1951 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 94)
  - Story Parade, Undated (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 95)
  - Thomas & Crowell Company, 1953 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 96)
  - Thomas Nelson & Sons, 1946 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 97)
  - Vogue, 1959 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 98)
  - This Week Magazine, 1959 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 99)
  - The Westminster Press, 1952 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 100)
  - Whittlesey House, 1953 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 101)
  - William Morrow & Company, 1951 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 102)
  - Wing, J, 1988 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 103)
  - John C. Winston Company, 1948-1952 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 104)
  - Young America Magazines, 1948-1949 (Box 3 (3-Correspondence), Folder 105)